[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So in our previous discussions, we've been focusing on the relationship
我们之前的讨论着重于数据点之间的关系
between data points, where we're plotting the data points as points.
我们在图上将这些数据点用点来表示
In some cases, you want to display more than just points, you want to display
有些时候 我们想要展示的不仅是点
shapes to represent the data, and in that case you want to pack the shapes together.
你还想用形状来代表数据 在这种情况下 你就需要将这些形状封装在一起
So here's an example called a word cloud, and this is basically the overview
这儿有个关键词云的例子 基本上就是我们
text from our data visualization course from the Coursera page.
Coursera网站上数据可视化这门课程文本的汇总
And I've just passed this through a web page called Wordle.net and
我用一个叫做Wordle.net的网站处理这些文本
it created this word cloud which basically displays the most common words,
然后它就生成了这个关键词云 这里面展示了最常见的一些独特的词
the words that are distinctive that aren't everyday words like the, and and.
不包括那些日常用词 例如 the 和 and
And words that are used multiple times get displayed larger than
出现频率高的词比低频率的词
the words that are smaller.
显示得大一些
And then there's a process that packs these words into a collection,
然后将这些词打包到一个集合
so instead of just displaying the words in order horizontally
所以你可能看到一个关键词的标签云
that you might see in a tag cloud, this word cloud is packed together.
而不是按顺序横着显示所有词
And there is a spiral algorithm that it uses
关键词云采用一种螺旋算法
to basically find a first open space to pack a new word in it.
在第一个空的位置放入一个新词
Tries to start with the largest words first and then packs in the small ones
从词频最高的词开始 然后再封装词频低的
later based on that same spiral trial and error techniques spiraling out from
然后用相同的螺旋测试和检错技术从中心
the middle to try to pack the words into the location that they'll fit into first.
向周围螺旋扩散 同时将词汇封装在合适它的位置
And so these techniques tend to use area as a measure, and
所以这些技术倾向于采用面积作为衡量方式
we've looked at area as a measure before.
我们以前了解过用面积作为衡量方式
It's a pretty good quantitative measure, but ordinal, it's not very good.
这是种很好的定量衡量方法 但是从排序角度来看就不是很好
Being able to tell whether two different shapes have the same area can be quite
判断不同的形状面积孰大孰小通常
difficult.
不容易的事情
So if you have consistent shapes.
所以如果不同样形状
It's hard to tell if I have the same amount of area in the blue circle as in
很难分辨蓝色圆形和橙色正方形
this orange square.
是否有同样大的面积
But if you have consistent shapes, if I have two circles,
但如果是同样的形状 比如两个圆形
then I can tell that the areas are the same based on the length.
我就可以通过长度来判断那个圆的面积大
And then if the shapes are aligned, if they share the same base,
那么如果这些形状是对齐的 如果它们有相同的底边
then I can just look at the height at the position, at the top and
那么我就可以只看高度 看位置 看顶部
tell if the orange circle is less than the blue circle in area.
来确定橙色圆圈的面积小于蓝色圆圈
And so area is very difficult to determine, especially
面积是很难确定的
when you have inconsistent shapes, but becomes useful if you have consistent and
尤其当形状不同的时候 但是当形状相同并对齐时就很有用
aligned shapes, because then you're using actual length and position.
因为你实际用的是长度和位置
Also area, as the area increases or decreases,
还有 面积增加或减少
the length is going to increase or decrease as the square root of the area,
长度增加或减少的是面积的平方根
and so that also complicates figuring out a quantitative difference between shapes.
所以很难定量的判断差别
And so, if we want to plot a bunch of data without any coordinates attached to it,
所以 如果我们不引用坐标系 来绘制一组数据
you could just pack the data together using, for example,
你可以就将数据叠放在一起
area to display the data.
然后用 比如说 面积来表示数据
So this is a Tableau plot of the population from our
图中所示是Tableau生成的WDI数据库中的人口数据
WDI database, and you can see some of the larger
可以看到一些大的圆形带有标签
items are labeled if the label will fit in the region, but
如果标签可以完全显示在区域内的话
here the area is basically indicating population, total number of people.
面积在这里只表示人口总数
The area is proportional to the number of people.
面积和人口是成比例的
And because these are all the same shape we can do a pretty good job of
因为这些图形的形状相同 我们可以很好的
finding an ordinal.
找到它们的序数关系
I can tell that China has more people than India.
可以看出中国人口比印度多
India has more people than United States.
印度人口比美国多
United States has more people than Brazi, and so on.
美国人口比巴西多 等等
And so we get a good indication, at least an ordinal indication,
所以我们可以很好的看出人口的差别
of the differences in population, and we don't need to use any other
至少可以看出顺序的差别 而且我们也不需要采用其他的坐标系
coordinates because we're we're just comparing the areas to each other.
因为我们就是在面积之间互相比较
We're not plotting anything horizontally or vertically,
我们没有把所有的数据都绘制在 水平或垂直的方向
we're just using the horizontal and vertical axis to keep our shapes disjoint.
我们只是用水平和垂直的坐标轴 来分散各个图形
So another way of plotting things horizontally or
另一种将数据横向或纵向表示的方法是
vertically is to display them on a map, and in this case,
在地图上制图 那么在这个例子中
we've distorted the map into a cartogram.
我们已经将地图变形成一个示意地图
Here's an ordinary atlas of the world, and here's that same atlas
上面是正常的世界地图 下面是同样的地图
distorted based on population, so that the amount of distortion,
根据人口进行变形 所以变形的程度
the area of the region is proportional to its population.
也就是说地区的面积是和当地人口成正比的
And you can see that certain regions have grown larger than they were before, and
可以看到某些地区的面积比以前要大好多
certain regions have grown to be much smaller.
而有些地区则变得比之前小好多
There's not very many people in Siberia, and so that's very small given it's area.
西伯利亚人口稀少 所以它在地图上占很小的面积
India and China have a lot of population,
印度和中国人口数量多
high population density, and so their regions have grown much larger.
人口密度大 所以这两个地区被拉得格外的大
In Africa you can see that Nigeria has grown to be quite large.
在非洲 可以看出尼日利亚占很大面积
And so this is a a way of indicating with area,
所以 这也是一种可以通过面积表达数据的方法
certain data that you would want to visualize.
可以更直观的看到某些数据
Again, it's relative.
这是相对的
It would be difficult to tell ordinally if the there's more people in for
这种方法很难区别顺序 比如在这张图上要判断
example, France or Germany, based on this display because the shapes are different,
法国和德国哪个人口更多就会很困难 因为两者形状不同
and it's difficult to judge area relationships between different shapes,
不同形状之间的面积关系也很难确定
but we can certainly tell that Germany is is roughly the same
但是我们肯定可以判断出德国 和以前的形状基本相同
shape it's just grown larger with a little bit of distortion than it was before.
只是面积稍微增大了一些
And so that's the distinction we're trying to make with the cartogram.
这就是我们想用示意地图来表现的差别
So how do you create those cartograms?
那么 如何创建示意地图呢
Well you start, in this case, with a grid of density data.
在这个例子中 你从一个密度数据的网格开始
And this is an old algorithm for doing this.
这是一种老算法了
There's better techniques that are more sophisticated but
现在有更好更成熟的技术
also much more complicated.
但同时也更复杂
This is a nice way to do it.
这里要讲的方法很容易实现
If you just fill a grid in with density data such as your local
如果你把密度数据填入网格中 例如本地人口密度数据
population density so within some unit area, what is the population density?
也就是在单位面积中 人口是多少
And so it could be heavily populated in this area and
所以可能在这个区域人口密度很高
lightly populated in these areas.
而在那边的区域里人口密度就比较低
And so you create a grid like that of rectangular cells and
那现在你创建一个像长方形单元格一样的网格
then you just scale each cell by that density value.
然后你将每一个单元格根据其密度值变形
So the squares that have a population density
所以那些密度值为0.5的正方形
of one-half get shrunk by one-half in area.
就被缩减为原来面积的一半
So that's about 70% horizontally and vertically.
也就是说水平和垂直方向都缩减70%
The areas that have population density one stay the same size, and
那些密度值为 1 的区域 面积保持不变
the areas that have larger population densities would grow proportionally, so
那些密度值大的区域 其面积也成比例增加
these squares would become twice as big, these squares become three times as big.
这些正方形将是原来的两倍大 而这些将是原来的三倍大
And then you can see that what we had as a grid before now becomes disconnected.
那么现在你可以看到我们原来的网格 现在已经支离破碎了
And so to reconnect it, we want to reconnect these corners to their average
要将这些单元格重新连结起来 我们就需要用一个平均值
of the four corners that shared that corner.
把它们共有的角连接起来
So we want to find a new point for
我们要为这个角找一个新的点
this corner equal to the average of these four previous corner points.
其位置为原来四个角点的平均值
So we create a new set of grid vertices equal
我们现在要创建一个新的网格的垂直边
to the average of the four grid vertices that shared them before.
新边长是原来这条边上四个网格变形后边长的平均值
Or three or two depending on, or one, if you're on the perimeter.
也可能是原来的三个 两个或者一个网格 取决于是否在周长上
And so we create this new grid and this new grid is deformed.
所以我们创建了一个新的网格 这个新网格是变形过的
And so based on this deformed grid We keep iterating that over and
再根据变形过的网格 我们重复这样的过程
over until we get a final deformed grid, and
知道得到一个最终的变形网格
then we look at the differences between the original grid points and
然后我们来观察原来网格的点和新的位置的差别
their new positions in the deformed grid that sets up a deformation.
由此来确定变形
It basically tells us what direction we should move data points.
我们基本上就由此可知应该 向哪个方向移动数据点
Then, we take our shape vertices of the outline data of our original map and
然后我们提取出原始地图中的数据的垂直边
deform them based on these arrows, and we can smoothly interpolate
根据这些箭头方向移动网格的顶点
these arrows if we need in between values in order to create the cartogram.
然后我们平缓的对这些网格定点进行插值计算 以确定最终的示意地图
Its basically,
基本上来说
we take a vector graphics representation of our data of our map and then deform
我们采用矢量图形代表我们的数据地图
the vertices based on this type of deformation to create the cartogram.
然后才用这种变形的方法来创建示意地图
So another technique that might be better than a cartogram is the ordinary
另一种可能优于示意地图的技术是
choropleth, and we see choropleths all the time.
普通标色图 我们经常可以看到标色图
It's basically data that's plotted over regions of a map.
基本上就是将数据绘制在地图的区域上
This is that same population data but
图里显示的是同样的人口数据
plotted inside the original outlines of our regions.
但是数据绘制在原有的区域边界里
In here, population is Is just given by the saturation of the color,
在这里 人口数据用颜色的不同饱和度来代表
and when we're looking at ordinal values,
当我们关注人口排序时
basically we can see that China has more population than India does,
我们可以看出中国比印度人口多
has more population than the U.S., which has more population than Brazil and so on.
也比美国人口多 美国人口比巴西多 等等
So you get a better indication of the order of these things from a chloropleth
所以从标色图中你能得到一个更直观的排序
than you might with a cardogram because area is such a poor indicator order,
而示意地图则不能 因为面积不宜作为顺序的指示值
whereas density saturation hue, density being intensity of a color or
然而 密度饱和色 也就是一种颜色的深浅 或者说
saturation in hue, are much better indicators of order.
色调的饱和度 则是更好的顺序指示值
So there's several techniques now for plotting data without using coordinate
那么我们刚才看到几种方法都可以绘制数据
data associated with the data for it's layout.
而不需采用坐标数据来关联数据的布局
We're deriving coordinate data.
其实还是源自于坐标数据
In these most recent examples we are using geographical data, where we have maybe
在刚才几个例子里 我们采用了地理数据
a region name, or a country name, and then we're deriving the actual coordinates of
我们可能用地区名或者国家名 然后我们倒出它们实际的坐标
that, perhaps an outline to fill in, or a location on a map to generate.
然后或者填充边长 或者生成位置
Or we're using some other packing or layout algorithm to distribute the data.
我们用其他的封装方式或者布局算法来分布数据
Those are all useful techniques in In the case where you've got data that you don't
这些都是很有用的技术 在你不想使用显式的坐标系时
want to use the explicit coordinates in the data as coordinates for their display.
可以考虑用这些技术展示数据
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community